Register of the China Defense Supplies Records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject file, 1941-1947 (Box 34-45)
  - Reports (Folder 42)
    - Purchase Negotiation Reports (Folder 42)
      - Correspondence and memoranda, 1941-1942 (Folder 42: 12)
      - Forms, 1941-1942 (Folder 42: 13)
      - Recommendations, 1941 (Folder 42: 14)
    - Report for Lombardo Toledano and Contreras on acquisition and export of materials to Mexico, 1941 (Folder 42: 15)
    - Supplement to Pro-Forma report, circa 1943 (Folder 42: 16)
    - Tweedy and Harding Reports, 1943-1944. (Folder 42: 17-18)
      Reports on India. Includes correspondence
    - Tweedy and Harding Reports, 1943-1944. (Folder 43: 1-2)
    - Tweedy and Harding Reports - Harding Report #8-11, 1943 (Folder 43: 3)
  - Reverse Lend-Lease, undated (Folder 43: 4)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1941-1942. (Folder 43: 5)
    Includes letter from Roosevelt to Soong
  - Routes from U.S. via Russia to China, 1942-1943 (Folder 43: 6)
  - Russo-Asiatic Bank litigation (Folder 42)
    - General, 1942-1944 (Folder 43: 7)
    - Yavdynsky, J.A., 1941-1943 (Folder 43: 8)
  - Screening Committee, 1944 (Folder 43: 9)
  - Secretary of War (Stimson, Henry L.), 1941-1942 (Folder 43: 10)
  - Shipbuilding workers, 1942 (Folder 43: 11)
  - Spare parts for P-40 machine guns, 1941-1942 (Folder 43: 12)
  - Stabilization of salaries, 1942 (Folder 43: 13)
  - State Department, 1941-1943 (Folder 43: 14-15)
  - State Department, Division of Cultural Relations, 1942-1943 (Folder 43: 16)
  - Stilwell, Joseph, 1942. (Folder 43: 17)
    Includes staff list and memorandum to Chiang Kai-shek concerning Stilwell's status
  - Storage facilities, 1941-1942 (Folder 43: 18)
  - Storage facilities, E. L. Matteson reports, 1941-1942 (Folder 44: 1)
  - Supply routes to China, 1942 (Folder 44: 2)
  - Tamb, Alex - Port programs, 1944-1945 (Folder 44: 3)
  - Timberman, Colonel, 1942 (Folder 44: 4)
  - Tire plant, 1942 (Folder 44: 5)
  - Thos. Cook and Sons, 1942 (Folder 44: 6-7)
  - Training films, 1943-1944 (Folder 44: 8)
  - Transportation of supplies through Burma to China, 1942. (Folder 44: 9)
    Includes memorandum to Chiefs of Staff
  - Treasury Department, 1942-1943 (Folder 44: 10)
  - Tungsten, 1942-1943 (Folder 44: 11)
  - United China Relief, 1942 (Folder 44: 12)
  - Universal Trading Corporation (Folder 44-45)
    - General, 1941-1944 (Folder 44: 13-14)
      Includes American Volunteer Group materials
    - Cash purchases, 1943-1944 (Folder 45: 1)
    - Purchases, 1941-1944. (Folder 45: 2)
    - Requirements, 1943, undated (Folder 45: 3)
  - U.S.S.R., oil and food supplies, 1941, undated (Folder 45: 4)
  - Visual training aid, 1944, undated (Folder 45: 5)
  - War Department, situation reports, 1942 (Folder 45: 6)
  - War Production Board, 1943-1944 (Folder 45: 7)
  - War Relief Control Board, 1942-1943 (Folder 45: 8)
  - Warships, 1944 (Folder 45: 9)
  - War situation, miscellaneous statements, 1942 (Folder 45: 10)
  - War strategy, 1942, undated (Folder 45: 11)
  - Water transport, 1946 (Folder 45: 12)
  - Welding electrodes, 1942-1943 (Folder 45: 13)
  - Whiten Machine Works, 1941-1942 (Folder 45: 14)
  - Wolfram, 1942 (Folder 45: 15)
  - Miscellany, 1941-1945 (Folder 45: 16)
- Oversize materials, 1941-1946 (Box 46-48)
  Includes financial documents, supply lists, and maps.
  - Balance sheets (bound volume), 1944-1946 (Folder 46)
  - Payroll, 1941-1946 (Folder 47: 1-4)
  - "Communications Between India and China" maps, undated. (Folder 48: 1)
    See also Subject file - India
  - Motor Transport/Transportation Department (Folder 48)
    - Statistics, 1941-1942 (Folder 48: 2)
    - Status of Requisition C-8, 1942 (Folder 48: 3)
  - Universal Trading Corporation, completed purchases, 1940-1944 (Folder 48: 4)
    See also Subject file
  - Oversize folder. Map of "Gya Lam" (The China Road), undated
    See also Subject files, India, "Communications Between India and China"
- Declassified U.S. government records released in 2013, 1940-1945
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes correspondence, memoranda, inventories of supplies and requisitions, and budgets.
  - General, 1941-1945 (Box 49)
    - Undated (Folder 49: 1)
    - 1941 (Folder 49: 2)
    - 1942 (Folder 49: 3)
    - 1943 (Folder 49: 4)
    - 1944 (Folder 49: 5)
    - 1945 (Folder 49: 6)
  - General office file, 1941-1944 (Box 49)
    - Administrative binder, 1942 (Folder 49: 7)
    - Correspondence of Whiting Willauer, 1941-1943 (Folder 49: 8-9)
    - History of China Defense Supplies, 1944 (Folder 49: 10)
    - Meetings, 1942-1943 (Folder 49: 11)
  - Departments file, 1940-1944 (Box 49-50)
    - Aviation Department, 1942-1943 (Folder 49: 12)
    - Motor Transport/Transportation Department, 1940-1943 (Folder 49: 13)
    - Motor Transport/Transportation Department (Contd.) (Folder 50: 1)
    - Ordnance Department, 1941-1944 (Folder 50: 2-3)
      Includes documents on the Emergency Air Transport Program
    - Signal Corps, 1942-1943 (Folder 50: 4-5)
  - American Volunteer Group (AVG)/Central Aircraft Manufacturing Company (CAMCO) file, 1941-1942 (Folder 50: 6-7)
  - Subject file, 1941-1945 (Box 50-51)
    - Air shipments from India to China, 1942-1944 (Folder 50: 8)
    - Budgets, 1941-1945 (Folder 50: 9)
    - Budgets (Contd.) (Folder 51: 1)
    - Chinese air cadets, 1942 (Folder 51: 2)
    - Gliders, 1941-1942 (Folder 51: 3)
    - Japanese aviation, 1943 (Folder 51: 4)
    - Lists of items available for transfer from defense aid appropriation, 1941 (Folder 51: 5-6)
    - Lists of materials floated or shipped, undated (Folder 51: 7-8)
    - Lists of materials floated or shipped (Contd.) (Folder 52: 1)
    - India-Iran-Russia supply route and Northwest Highway, 1943 (Folder 52: 2)
    - Inventory of supplies in India, 1943 (Folder 52: 3)
    - Maps, undated (Folder 52: 4)
    - Requisitions and records of inventory, 1941-1943 (Folder 52: 5-7)
    - Shipments, 1941-1942 (Folder 52: 8-10)
      Includes shipments related to the Emergency Air Transport Program
    - Supplies issued to Chinese troops in India, 1944 (Folder 52: 11)